Guide to the Bill Bytsura ACT UP Photography Collection 1981-2012 (Bulk 1989-1997) MSS.313
Fales Library and Special Collections
Bill Bytsura ACT UP Photography Collection
1981-2012
1989-1997
Fales Library and Special Collections
Bytsura, Bill
MSS.313
12.25 Linear Feet in 18 manuscript boxes, 1 half manuscript box, 2 record cartons, 2 oversize flat boxes, and 1 binder
Bill Bytsura is a photographer who extensively documented ACT UP and other unaffiliated AIDS awareness movements across the United States and in Europe throughout the late 1980s and 1990s. The collection includes studio-style portraits of each activist, along with their personal statements. Portraits include prominent activists such as Larry Kramer, Ann Northrop, Tim Bailey, Luke Sissyfag Montgomery, Didier Lestrade, Peter Staley, and Terry Stogdell. The collection also documents AIDS demonstrations, political funerals, and related publications.
Related Materials
Jay Blotcher Papers (MSS.137)
Scope and Content
The Bill Bytsura ACT UP Photography collection documents AIDS activism across the United States and Europe from 1989 through the late 1990's. Portraits include prominent activists such as Larry Kramer, Ann Northrop, Tim Bailey, Luke Sissyfag Montgomery, Didier Lestrade, Peter Staley, and Terry Stogdell. The collection also documents demonstrations, political funerals, and related publications.
The collection consists of photographs, contact sheets, negatives, and slides; press in the form of magazines and articles; promotional materials such as t-shirts, hats, and buttons; printed ephemera such as posters, postcards, flyers, and stickers, and administrative files, including release forms and correspondence.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Fales Library and Special Collections, fales.library@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596.
Biographical Note
Bill Bytsura is an American photographer born in 1956 in Plattsburg, New York. Bytsura moved to New York City in 1980 and lived in the East Village for 30 years. A self-taught photographer, he began his photography career after finding his father's old Minolta SRT–101 camera and becoming fascinated by what it could capture.
During the late 1980s, after the death of his partner, Randy Northup, he was prominent in the AIDS activist movement. He became a member of ACT UP and joined the ACT UP Media Committee with fellow member Jay Blotcher. Bytsura started his AIDS activist project as a way to shed light on the disparity between how AIDS activists were being portrayed in the media and how he saw them at the meetings and protests.
Bytsura began the AIDS activist project in New York City in 1989, and continued to photograph AIDS activists throughout the United States and parts of Europe throughout the 1990s. The work consists of studio-style black and white portraits of each activist, accompanied by a personal statement. In 1992 Bytsura went, camera in hand, to the AIDS Conference in Amsterdam, and in 1993 to the AIDS Conference in Berlin. He documented AIDS activists in Paris, as well as Miami, Ft. Lauderdale, San Francisco, Los Angeles, St. Louis, Atlanta, Miami, and Puerto Rico. This work was shown in numerous galleries in the East Village, and was included in the exhibit "Don't Leave Me This Way, Art in the Age of AIDS" at the Australian National Gallery in 1995. Bytsura's work has appeared in several magazines, including The New York Times Magazine.
Bill Bytsura moved to Panama City, Panama in 2011. He is currently working on photography projects with foundations whose goal is to help children from disadvantaged backgrounds find opportunity and hope through music. He is additionally working on a project photographing the people of Panama as they are now, as the country goes through major growth, to preserve the words and faces of the Panamanian people.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series. All series are arranged alphabetically except for Series II, which is arranged chronologically.
Series I: Portraits contains photographs, contact sheets, negatives, release forms and statements. The dates finding aid dates reflect the date of printing. When identifiable, the release forms have been left together with photographs. There is a separate folder titled "release forms" for unidentified release forms.
Series II: Demonstrations contains photographs, contact sheets, negatives and slides. The finding aid dates reflect the date of printing, as that was the photographer's method of notation. In some instances, the dates of printing are the same or extremely close to the estimated date of the event the prints describe. In other instances, the dates of printing are separated by a few years from the event. In this case, the date of the event, if known, is included in the title. Negatives that were found loose have been separated by year, and may contain some portraits as well as documentation of demonstrations or events.
Series III: Press, Promotion, and Adminstrative Files includes articles and magazines featuring Bytsura's work, as well as promotional materials and objects such as t-shirts, a hat and buttons, and a few administrative items such as budgets.
Series IV: Ephemera includes a hat, t-shirts, stickers, pins and postcards.
Oversize materials are listed at the end of the finding aid:
Series I Oversize: Portraits
Series II Oversize: Demonstrations
Series III Oversize: Press, Promotion, and Adminstrative Files
Series IV Oversize: Posters
Provenance
The Bill Bytsura ACT UP Photography Collection was donated to NYU's Fales Library by Bill Bytsura in 2011.
Physical Characteristics and Technical Requirements
Born-digital materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers.
Color slides.; Portrait prints |y 20th century.; Demonstrations.; Negatives (photographic); Contact sheets.; Photographic prints.; Printed ephemera.; AIDS International.; AIDS activists.; AIDS (Disease); Correspondence.; Buttons (information artifacts).; Activism (LGBTQ); Gay activists -- New York (State) -- New York.; AIDS (Disease) |x Social aspects |z New York (State) |z New York.; AIDS (Disease) and mass media.; Gay liberation movement.; Bytsura, Bill; Gay Men's Health Crisis, Inc.; ACT UP (Organization); ACT UP New York (Organization); Kramer, Larry
- Series I: Portraits
  Scope and Content
  Series I: Portraits contains photographs, contact sheets, negatives, release forms and statements. The dates finding aid dates reflect the date of printing. When identifiable, the release forms have been left together with photographs. There is a separate folder titled "release forms" for unidentified release forms.
  - [ACT UP Paris], August 19, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Acosta, Ruben, May 15, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Agosto, Moises, December 21, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Arn, Tony and Max, April 2, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Aston, Tay, May 10, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Aubrey, Emmanuel, May 26, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bailey, Tim, May 26, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bannino, Vannesa, October 15, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Barnhardt, Kate, October 15, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Baudelaire, Virginia [Paris], May 22, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Belverio, Glenn, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Benedicte, Gallienne [Paris], May 22, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Bennett, Anthony, February 16, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Bennett, Mona, May 1, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Blotcher, Jay Bruce, June 4, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Bodelier, Oscar, August 17, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Bois, Jean-Rene, May 22, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Boyles, Jude [UK], October 15, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Brand, Charles, January 9, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Braverman, G'dali, March 28, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Brockel, Kathleen [Atlanta], May 1, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Broome, Neil, July 10, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Brown, David C. and John J. Winters, April 2, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Calsa, Michael, undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Campbell, John, August 19, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Campbell, Peggy Taylor, April 24, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Camunas, Manuel, August 15, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Canpilo, Robin [Paris], October 15, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Carpoor, Carmen, July 10, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Cashman, Peter, May 10, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Caso, Ed, April 2, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Constantino, Arlindo, May 8, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - [contact sheets, unidentified], August 26, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - [contact sheets, unidentified], October 15, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - [contact sheets, unidentified], October 15, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - [contact sheets, unidentified], May 6, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - [contact sheets, unidentified], March 10, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - [contact sheets, unidentified], March 25, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - [contact sheets, unidentified], March 25, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - [contact sheets, unidentified], March 25, 1998 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - [contact sheets, unidentified], March 25, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - [contact sheets, unidentified], April 2, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - [contact sheets, unidentified], April 2, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - [contact sheets, unidentified], April 2, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - [contact sheets, unidentified], May 10, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - [contact sheets, unidentified], May 10, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - [contact sheets, unidentified], May 10, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Contini, Alan, July 20, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Cooper, Charlene [Stand Up Harlem], December 12, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Corbin, Marc [Miami], May 2, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Crawshaw, Gill; Ward, Mick, August 19, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Crean, Robert [Atlanta], May 2, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Croall, Ben, August 19, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Cunningham, Ineke, August 15, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Cunningham, Tom, June 11, 1990 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Cylar, Keith, April 2, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - d'Adesky, Anne-Christine, October 15, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - d'Ameson [D'ois Adamson, stand up Harlem], May 3, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Daniels, Paul [Golden Gate], May 10, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Daniels, Phyllis; Rivera, Clara, May 3, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Daniels, Phyllis [Stand Up Harlem], February 2, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Davids, Julie [Philadelphia], October 15, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - De Goei, Tanne [Amsterdam], August 19, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - De Haro, Sarah; Patouillard, Victoria, May 18, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - DeLeon, Dennis, undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Dennery, Denis, May 18, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - De Sousa, Paulo, August 6, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Diamond, Joel; Lafoon, Brad [Atlanta], May 1, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - DiPaulo, Joey, December 31, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - D'nai, Romeo [Atlanta], November 20, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Duane, Tom, January 30, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Duarte, Ricardo [Toront, Berlin], October 15, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Duchene, Laurence, undated (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Dudon, Lilian, May 19, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Elsterhof, [Else]; Wulf, Andreas [Berlin, drag], October 15, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Ewing, Larry, August 17, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Farber, Robert, July 18, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Fauchois, Gwen, undated (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Feinberg, Weir, July 10, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Fell, Blair, January 30, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Feuchot, Patricia, May 19, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Fleck, Dave, December 15, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Fleutelot, Eric [Paris], May 26, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Fons, Christopher, May 7, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Fontan, Nicole, May 1995 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Formant, Phillipa [Paris], May 1995 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Frigiolini, Michela [Paris], undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Gabi and Abi, August 19, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Gagliostro, Vincent, November 21, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Garance, Francke-Ruta, July 10, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Garcia, Robert, June 11, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Garel, Valerie; Mangeot, Philippe, May 26, 1995 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Gekeler, Corinna, May 19, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Genet, Florence [Paris], May 23, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Gerhandt, Greg, May 14, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Getty, Jeff, September 16, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Geyer, Hans-Jorg, August 17, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Giamattei, Pierre, January 1, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Girotti, Carlos, August 19, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Goldberg, Ron, July 10, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Gould, Harley [Atlanta], May 2, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Graff, Michael, February 16, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Graham, Jeff; Stinner, Peter [Atlanta], May 2, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Gray, Natasha, January 28, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Greenough, Dene; Martin, Floyd [Atlanta], April 4, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Greenspan, Judy, May 10, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Gura, Jeanne Goldie; Gura, Stephen [Atlanta], May 2, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Hammerstaedt, Betina [Berlin], August 17, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Haneef, Balil, May 3, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Haner, Hal, undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Harris, Sarah J. [Amsterdam], August 19, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Hartley, Michael, October 15, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Haveter, Robin, January 30, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Hayworth, Christina, August 15, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Hensler, Rebecca, January 1992 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Hilferty, Robert, July 26, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Houghton, Juliet [UK], October 15, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Hubert, Dareau, May 26, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Hulse, Jimmy, May 10, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Irizanny-Vizcarrondo, Georgie, August 14, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Iversen, John [East Bay], March 25, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Jennings, David [UK], August 19, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Johnson, Saundra, October 15, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Jones, Louis, February 26, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Jones, Stephanie M., January 16, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Killick, Chris, August 17, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - King, Charles, September 17, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Kloster, Ivonne; Alan Peters, Tabitha [Dallas], May 14, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Kompier, Resi, August 17, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Kramer, Larry, August 26, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Languerand, Emeric [Park], October 15, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Lasnier, Philippe [Paris], May 22, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Laurent, Concourdel, undated (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Le Pen, Anne [Paris], undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Lestrade, Didier, May 24, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Lewis, Ronald [Harlem], May 3, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Loftus, Rick [Richard A., Dr.], June 23, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Lopez, Louis; Sawyer, Eric, August 26, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Lopez, Michelle, undated (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Lorna [Harlem], May 3, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Maggenti, Maria, November 21, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Maldonado, Minerva [Stand Up Harlem], January 30, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Manhoff, Ira, July 10, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Marks, Joel, undated (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Marley, Kim [St. Louis], January 18, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Marras, Amerigo, November 8, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Martet, Christophe [Paris], May 24, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Martinet, Stephane, December 21, 1990 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Maynard, Brenda, February 12, 1994 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Mazyck, Joyce, May 14, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - McGarry, Tim, November 26, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - McKean, Aldyn, January 4, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - McVey-Russell, Gregory A. (Gar), May 10, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Mely, Sylvan [Paris], June 6, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Menager, Yves, undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Mendez, Juan, February 25, 1991 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Meyhdert [Amsterdam Rai Center], August 13, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Morales, Mykl and Ronnas [Kansas City], May 14, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Nalick, Mary, March 25, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Navarro, Patricia, April 2, 1998 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Nectar, Marc [Paris], May 19, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Nicholson-Earle, Brent, June 11, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Northrop, Anne, June 11, 1990 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Nouvelot, Emmanuel [Paris], May 15, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Nutland, Will [Norwich], August 19, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - O, May 2, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Osorio, Marco Antonio, May 8, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Ott, Andy, October 15, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Otter, Kathy, January 30, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Palmer, Marvin, January 18, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Paravicini, V., October 15, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Parks, Virginia [San Francisco], October 15, 1993, April 26, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Pasco, Larry David, May 14, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Pauvert, Stephane [Paris], May 24, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Payan, Ilka Tanya, August 15, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Pepiot, Dominique [Paris], May 23, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Perkins, David Lee, March 25, 1998 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Perri, Anthony [Buffalo], May 7, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Phillips, Suzanne [Dr.], October 26, 1990 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Pickel, Jo-Anne [Montreal], August 19, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Poindexter, Dorothy, February 5, 1994 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - [Portraits Slides], undated (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - [Portraits, unidentified], undated (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Potiron, Cegric [Paris], May 18, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Prigent, Lok [Paris], undated (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - Provenzano, Jim, January 1, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - [Puerto Rico], 1994 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - [Puerto Rico], 1994 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - [Puerto Rico, Contact Sheets], December 31, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - [Puerto Rico, Papers], May 6, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Queer Nation Underwear Party Invite, April 3, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Querelle T Shirt, June 1, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Regnier, Jean Christian, May 30, 1995 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - [Release Forms], 1992-1997 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Rivera, Lucy [Stand Up Harlem], February 5, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Robinson, Dave, January 28, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Roland, Nicolas [Paris], March 27, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Rollerina, January 1, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Ronnelae, Denis, August 13, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Rosario, Mia Lynn, April 4, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Roth, Helles, June 6, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Rowan, Chip, April 4, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Russeau, Anne, undated (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Salters, Brenda, February 5, 1994 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Sarandon, Susan, July 17, 1996 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Schillon, Manfred, August 13, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Schleimer, Sara; Lurie, Nadine, March 25, 1998 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Seggerman, Maryann G. C. [Connecticut], November 8, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Sharp, Matthew, April 2, 1998 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Sigmon, Carl, January 1, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Signorella, Mike, May 25, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Simon, Gloria, July 23, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Sissyfag, Luke [Montgomery], May 14, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Solemes, Boris [Paris], May 18, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Sorge, Rod, September 19, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - [Stand Up Harlem, Unidentified] 1 of 2, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - [Stand Up Harlem, Unidentified] 2 of 2, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - St. Angelo, Madrid, May 14, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Staley, Peter, December 8, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - [Stephanie, Act Up Paris], undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Stogdell, Terry and Desiree [Father-Daughter San Francisco], June 23, 1997 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Tarbe, Gerard [Paris], May 18, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Teigeler, David [Amsterdam], August 17, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Tenstermache, Klaus, October 15, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Tigger, August 13, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Traumatola, Sharon [Tratamola?], September 19, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Turkott, Jim, November 19, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Turner, Wayne; Michael, Steve [DC], May 1, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Unidentified Portraits, January 30, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Uribe Torres, Oscar [Ft. Lauderdale], August 19, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Vazquez, Robert, undated (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Velez, Andy, January 10, 1995 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Vellay, Cleevus, October 15, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Verhoef, Henk, August 19, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Vidal-Ortiz, Salvador, August 15, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Vitale, Bruno, January 18, 1993 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Vlasveld, Lizet [Amsterdam], August 19, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Voelcker, John, January 30, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Vos, Frank [Amsterdam], August 13, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Various portraits: contact sheets, 1990s (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Various portraits: negatives (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Wagner, Jim, January 28, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Walker, Dorothy [Stand Up Harlem], May 14, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Warner, Stephanie, May 25, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Weeks, Jerry, November 19, 1991 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Weissner, Mitch [Miami], April 4, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Wieder, Harry, February 16, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Wiederman, Adrian [Munich], October 15, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Wiggins, Michael, September 19, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Williams, Cheryl [Atlanta], April 4, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Williams, Dan, September 17, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Wolfe, Maxine, August 26, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - [Woman from LA], August 19, 1992 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Won, John, January 10, 1995 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Zwickler, Phil, January 30, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 16)
- Series II: Demonstrations
  Series II: Demonstrations contains photographs, contact sheets, negatives and slides. The finding aid dates reflect the date of printing, as that was the photographer's method of notation. In some instances, the dates of printing are the same or extremely close to the estimated date of the event the prints describe. In other instances, the dates of printing are separated by a few years from the event. In this case, the date of the event, if known, is included in the title. Negatives that were found loose have been separated by year, and may contain some portraits as well as documentation of demonstrations or events.
  - Gay Pride 1981, June 28, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - ATR Benefit/ AIDS Treatment Registry, January 1, 1989; March 13, 1990; September 12, 1992; September 29, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - January 24, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - February 21, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - November 2, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - [Birthday], November 21, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - February 26, 1991 [Activistas Latinas, Political Funeral] (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - July 10, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - November 21, 1990 [Public Impact- Jay Blotcher], August 6, 1991; December 15, 1997; May 10, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - September 16, 1991 [Ann Northup, Stop Forced HIV Testing], August 6, 1991; September 16, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - September 27, 1991 [Office] Kenne Bunkport (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - November 19, 1991 [Bush Protest] (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Negatives 1992 [Act Up NY; Act Up Amsterdam; Act Up Fisher], October 11, 1992; August 19, 1992; November 10, 1992; December 31, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - [Act Up Demonstrations: Washington DC], 1992 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Exhibition [undated], February 24, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - [VIII International Conference of AIDS: July 19-24, 1992], August 19, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - [NYC undated], September 16, 1992; August 19, 1992 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - September 19, 1992 [Hate is not a cure] (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - [Act Up Ashes], November 10, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 1)